<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ArrayOfOnThisDay xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2002</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>1</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2002 the euro, the monetary unit of the European Union, was introduced with the issuance of both currency and coins, and by March 2002 it was the sole legal tender of participating member states.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1492</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>2</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1492, Granada, home of the Alhambra palace and the seat and final stronghold of the Moorish kingdom in Spain, was surrendered to the Catholic Monarchs, Ferdinand II and Isabella I, ending the Reconquest.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1521</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>3</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1521, Pope Leo X issued the papal bull Decet Romanum Pontificem, excommunicating Martin Luther, the German priest whose questioning of certain Roman Catholic practices initiated the Protestant Reformation.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1948</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>4</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1948, the Southeast Asian nation of Burma (Myanmar) formally gained independence, completing the transfer of power negotiated by Burmese leader Aung San and British Prime Minister Clement Attlee in 1947.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1933</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>5</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>In San Francisco on this day in 1933, construction began on the Golden Gate Bridge, a suspension bridge that once boasted the longest main span in the world and that has been celebrated for the magnificence of its setting.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2021</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>6</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info> Supporters of President Donald Trump stormed the U.S. Capitol, where Congress was meeting to certify Joe Biden's win in the 2020 election; Trump and his backers alleged widespread voter fraud, though there was no evidence for the claims.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2001</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>7</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info> John Kufuor was inaugurated as president of Ghana in that country's first peaceful transition from one elected government to another.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1997</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>8</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1997, the principality of Monaco began a yearlong celebration in honour of the 700th anniversary of the rule of the Grimaldi family, who seized power in 1297 and gained firm possession of Monaco in 1419.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2005</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>9</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Mahmoud Abbas, who was a founder of Fatah in the 1950s and served briefly as prime minister of the Palestinian Authority (PA) in 2003 under Yasir ?Arafat, was elected president of the PA on this day in 2005.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1776</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>10</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1776, Thomas Paine published Common Sense, a 50-page pamphlet that sold more than 500,000 copies within a few months and called for a war of independence that would become the American Revolution.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1935</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>11</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1935, Amelia Earhart, one of the world's most celebrated aviators, made the first successful solo flight from Hawaii to California, a distance longer than that from the United States to Europe.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2010</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>12</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2010, a magnitude-7.0 earthquake devastated Haiti, especially Port-au-Prince, killing more than 200,000 people and leaving more than 1,000,000 homeless and touching off a massive international relief effort.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1898</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>13</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1898, French author ?mile Zola published an open letter in the newspaper L'Aurore denouncing the French general staff for its role in the 1894 treason conviction of Jewish French army officer Alfred Dreyfus.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1900</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>14</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The opera Tosca-a psychological drama of deceit and doubt composed by Giacomo Puccini, one of the greatest exponents of operatic realism-made its world premiere in Rome's Costanzi Theatre on this day in 1900.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1759</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>15</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Established by an act of Parliament in 1753, the British Museum-which counts among its world-renowned antiquities and archaeological holdings the Elgin Marbles and the Rosetta Stone-opened to the public this day in 1759.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1991</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>16</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Persian Gulf War, triggered by Iraq's occupation of Kuwait in August 1990, began on this day in 1991 with a U.S.-led air offensive against Iraq that continued until a cease-fire was declared on February 28.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1893</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>17</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Acting for Hawaiian sugar interests and their American allies, a committee led by Sanford Ballard Dole deposed Hawaiian Queen Liliuokalani this day in 1893 and installed a provisional government with Dole as president.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1871</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>18</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The German Empire, forged as a result of diplomacy rather than an outpouring of popular nationalist feeling, was founded this day in 1871 in the aftermath of three successful wars by the North German state of Prussia.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1966</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>19</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Following the sudden death of Indian Premier Lal Bahadur Shastri eight days earlier, Indira Gandhi became prime minister of India on this day in 1966, assuming the office first held by her father, Jawaharlal Nehru.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2009</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>20</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2009, Barack Obama was sworn in as the 44th president of the United States, becoming the first African American to hold the office.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1976</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>21</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Generating a sonic boom as it traveled through the atmosphere at supersonic speed, the Concorde, a commercial aircraft built with funding from the British and French governments, began regular service on this day in 1976.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1973</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>22</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1973, the U.S. Supreme Court issued one of its most momentous decisions, ruling in Roe v. Wade that a Texas statute criminalizing abortion in most instances violated a woman's constitutional right of privacy.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1997</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>23</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1997, Madeleine Albright, who had earlier served as U.S. ambassador to the UN, assumed under President Bill Clinton the office of secretary of state, becoming the first woman to hold that cabinet post.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2004</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>24</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Launched in mid-2003, the six-wheeled robotic rover Opportunity landed on Mars this day in 2004 and-like its twin rover, Spirit, which had landed on January 3-analyzed rocks and soils and relayed pictures back to Earth.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>41</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>25</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 41 ce Claudius I, who extended Roman rule in North Africa and made Britain a province of the Roman Empire, was affirmed as emperor, raised to the post one day after the murder of his nephew, Gaius Caesar (Caligula).</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1788</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>26</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1788, Arthur Phillip, who had sailed into what is now Sydney Cove with a shipload of convicts, hoisted the British flag and established the first permanent European settlement on the continent of Australia.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1973</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>27</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Paris accord ending the Vietnam War, America's longest war to that time, was signed this day in 1973, providing for an exchange of prisoners and for the unilateral withdrawal of U.S. forces from South Vietnam.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1986</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>28</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1986, the U.S. space shuttle Challenger exploded 73 seconds after liftoff from Florida, killing all seven aboard, including a schoolteacher who had been chosen as the first American civilian to travel in space.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2002</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>29</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2002, U.S. President George W. Bush, delivering a State of the Union address, described Iraq, Iran, and North Korea as an "axis of evil" for their attempts to develop nuclear, chemical, or biological weaponry.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1948</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>30</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Indian leader Mahatma Gandhi-considered the father of his country and internationally esteemed for his doctrine of nonviolent protest (satyagraha) to achieve political and social progress-was assassinated on this day in 1948.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1606</Year>
      <Month>1</Month>
      <Day>31</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1606, British provocateur Guy Fawkes-one of the Gunpowder Plot conspirators, who sought to blow up Parliament and to assassinate King James I for his repression of Roman Catholics-was executed in London.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2003</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>1</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2003, while returning to Earth from an orbital mission, the U.S. space shuttle Columbia broke up catastrophically at an altitude of about 40 miles (60 km) over Texas, killing all seven crew members.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1990</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>2</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1990, South African President F.W. de Klerk lifted the 30-year ban on the African National Congress, resulting in the release from prison of Nelson Mandela and marking the beginning of the end of apartheid.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1870</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>3</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1870, the Fifteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States was ratified, guaranteeing the right to vote regardless of race and intending to ensure, with the Fourteenth Amendment, the civil rights of former slaves.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1945</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>4</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1945, during the final stages of World War II, the Yalta Conference opened with Franklin D. Roosevelt, Winston Churchill, and Joseph Stalin meeting to plan the final defeat and occupation of Nazi Germany.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1985</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>5</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info> Portuguese football (soccer) player Cristiano Ronaldo, one of the finest forwards of his generation, was born in Funchal, Portugal.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1952</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>6</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Elizabeth II, who celebrated her Golden Jubilee in 2002, ascended the throne of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland this day in 1952, following the death of her father, King George VI.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1964</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>7</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The musical British Invasion began when the Beatles landed in New York City this day in 1964, and two nights later, as Beatlemania stormed America, their performance on The Ed Sullivan Show was watched by 73 million viewers.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1587</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>8</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Mary, Queen of Scots, rival of Queen Elizabeth I of England, was beheaded this day in 1587 at Fotheringhay Castle, her execution a chilling scene redeemed by the great personal dignity with which she met her fate.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1757</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>9</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Concluded this day in 1757 by Robert Clive, the Treaty of Alinagar restored Calcutta (now Kolkata)-which Clive had recovered in January from Siraj al-Dawlah-to British control and served as a prelude to the seizure of Bengal.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1996</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>10</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1996, world chess champion Garry Kasparov began a six-round match against Deep Blue, a chess-playing computer built by IBM, in which Kasparov claimed a 4-2 victory (though Deep Blue won a rematch the following year).</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1858</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>11</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1858 in Lourdes, France, 14-year-old Bernadette Soubirous, a miller's daughter, first had visions of the Virgin Mary that were authenticated by Pope Pius IX in 1862, initiating the cult of Our Lady of Lourdes.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1818</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>12</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Although the decisive victory over the Spanish did not come until April at the Battle of Maipú, Chile formally declared independence from Spain on this day in 1818, the first anniversary of Chile's victory at Chacabuco.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1689</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>13</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Following the Glorious Revolution, William and Mary were proclaimed king and queen of England this day in 1689, after which they ruled jointly as King William III and Queen Mary II until her death in 1694.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1989</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>14</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1989, Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini of Iran issued a fatwa and offered a bounty for the assassination of author Salman Rushdie, whose novel The Satanic Verses (1988) Khomeini denounced as blasphemous.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1898</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>15</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1898, an explosion in Havana harbour sank the battleship USS Maine, killing 260 American seamen and precipitating the Spanish-American War, which originated in the Cuban struggle for independence from Spain.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1959</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>16</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>After defeating the forces of dictator General Fulgencio Batista, Fidel Castro became premier of Cuba this day in 1959 and transformed the island country into the Western Hemisphere's first communist state.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1979</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>17</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>After the Vietnam War, Vietnam bolstered its ties with the Soviet Union rather than with China, and, following a series of anti-Chinese, pro-Soviet maneuvers by Vietnam, China invaded its southern neighbour this day in 1979.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1930</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>18</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Using a 13-inch (33-cm) telescope at the Lowell Observatory in Flagstaff, Arizona, Clyde W. Tombaugh, a 24-year-old American with no formal training in astronomy, discovered the dwarf planet Pluto this day in 1930.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1945</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>19</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1945, during the final phases of World War II, U.S. Marines invaded Iwo Jima so as to wrest control of the strategically important island from the Japanese, who put up fierce resistance in the ensuing battle.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1962</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>20</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>John H. Glenn, Jr., the oldest of seven astronauts selected by NASA for Project Mercury spaceflight training (and later a U.S. senator), became on this day in 1962 the first American to orbit Earth, doing so three times.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1965</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>21</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Malcolm X, who articulated concepts of racial pride and black nationalism in the United States, was assassinated this day in 1965 and became an ideological hero after the posthumous release of The Autobiography of Malcolm X.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1997</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>22</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1997, a team of British scientists working under the direction of Ian Wilmut at the Roslin Institute near Edinburgh announced the birth of Dolly the sheep, the first clone of an adult mammal.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1836</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>23</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>This day in 1836, during the Texas war for independence, Mexican General Antonio López de Santa Anna began a siege of the Alamo, which was captured after 13 days and which became for Texans a symbol of heroic resistance.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1868</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>24</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1868, the U.S. House of Representatives voted 126-47 to impeach President Andrew Johnson, whose lenient Reconstruction policies regarding the South after the Civil War angered Radical Republicans in Congress.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1986</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>25</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1986, Philippine President Ferdinand E. Marcos, under pressure from the United States, fled his country for Hawaii after a fraudulent electoral victory over Corazon Aquino, who replaced him as president.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1815</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>26</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Forced to abdicate as French emperor in 1814, Napoleon escaped from exile on the island of Elba this day in 1815 and, gathering support en route, retook power on his return to Paris on March 20, ushering in the Hundred Days.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2010</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>27</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2010, a magnitude-8.8 earthquake struck Chile, causing widespread damage and triggering a tsunami that devastated coastal areas; it was the most powerful earthquake to strike the region since 1960.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1986</Year>
      <Month>2</Month>
      <Day>28</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Olof Palme, the internationally prominent prime minister of Sweden (1969-76, 1982-86) whose strong pacifist beliefs included opposition to the Vietnam War, was assassinated this day in Stockholm in 1986.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1872</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>1</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Yellowstone National Park, situated in the western United States and designated a UNESCO World Heritage site in 1978, was established by the U.S. Congress as the country's-and the world's-first national park this day in 1872.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1956</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>2</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The North African country of Morocco, situated directly across the Strait of Gibraltar from Spain, proclaimed independence from France this day in 1956, the sultan Muhammad V having formed its first government.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2005</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>3</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2005, American adventurer Steve Fossett became the first person to complete a solo nonstop circumnavigation of the globe without refueling when he landed in Kansas after more than 67 hours in flight.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1933</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>4</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1933, in the midst of the Great Depression, Franklin D. Roosevelt was inaugurated as the 32nd U.S. president, and later he led the country out of the Depression and to victory in World War II.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1770</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>5</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Harassed by a mob, British troops on this day in 1770 opened fire, killing Crispus Attucks and four others in the Boston Massacre, an event that galvanized anti-British feelings in the lead-up to the American Revolution.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1924</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>6</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1924, the Egyptian government opened the mummy case of King Tutankhamen, ruler of Egypt in the 14th century bce, whose burial chamber had been discovered in 1922 by renowned British archaeologist Howard Carter.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1965</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>7</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1965, state troopers used nightsticks and tear gas to attack American civil rights activists as they crossed a bridge in Selma, Alabama, during their attempted march to the state capitol in Montgomery.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1702</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>8</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1702, Anne became the last Stuart monarch of Great Britain, having earlier acquiesced to the Act of Settlement of 1701, which designated as her successors the Hanoverian descendants of King James I.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1862</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>9</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1862 during the American Civil War, the ironclads Monitor and Virginia (formerly Merrimack) battled in the harbour at Hampton Roads, Virginia, marking the beginning of a new era of naval warfare.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1933</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>10</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1933, soon after Adolf Hitler became chancellor, the first concentration camp in Germany opened at Dachau, where at least 32,000 people would die from disease, malnutrition, physical oppression, and execution.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2011</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>11</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2011, an earthquake struck off the northeastern coast of Honshu, Japan, causing widespread damage in the country and triggering a devastating tsunami that instigated a major nuclear accident.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1947</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>12</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1947, U.S. President Harry S. Truman articulated what became known as the Truman Doctrine when he asked Congress to appropriate aid for Greece and Turkey, both of which were facing communist threats.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1781</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>13</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>English astronomer William Herschel observed this day in 1781 the seventh planet from the Sun, Uranus-first described by him as "a curious either nebulous star or perhaps a comet" and named for the father of the god Saturn.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2004</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>14</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Vladimir Putin, the intelligence officer and politician who became president of Russia in 1999 upon the resignation of Boris Yeltsin, was overwhelmingly reelected to a second term as president this day in 2004.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2019</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>15</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info> More than 1.5 million students participated in climate change protests around the world as part of Fridays for Future, a movement started by Swedish environmental activist Greta Thunberg.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1968</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>16</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1968, during the Vietnam War, U.S. soldiers dispatched on a search-and-destroy mission killed as many as 500 unarmed villagers in the hamlet of My Lai, considered a stronghold of the Viet Cong.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1992</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>17</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1992, nearly 69 percent of white South African voters backed F.W. de Klerk's reforms-which included the repeal of racially discriminatory laws-and effectively endorsed the dismantling of apartheid.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2000</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>18</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2000, Chen Shui-bian, a leader of the pro-independence movement that sought statehood for the Republic of China (Taiwan), was elected president of Taiwan, breaking the Nationalist Party's 55-year rule.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2003</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>19</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2003, U.S. President George W. Bush ordered air strikes on Baghdad, thus launching the Iraq War to oust dictator Saddam Hussein, who was believed (wrongly) to be manufacturing weapons of mass destruction.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1995</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>20</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Top leaders of AUM Shinrikyo (Japanese: "AUM Supreme Truth"), a Japanese Buddhist sect founded in 1987 by Asahara Shoko, released nerve gas into a Tokyo subway this day in 1995, killing 12 people and injuring thousands.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1963</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>21</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The U.S. federal prison on San Francisco Bay's Alcatraz Island, which had held some of the most dangerous civilian prisoners-including Al Capone and Robert Stroud, the "Birdman of Alcatraz"-was closed this day in 1963.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1765</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>22</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1765 the British Parliament passed the Stamp Act, which placed taxes on various printed papers in the colonies; highly unpopular, the legislation was particularly contentious in America.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1806</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>23</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Having completed the first U.S. overland expedition to the Pacific coast, explorers Meriwether Lewis and William Clark this day in 1806 began their return to St. Louis, Missouri, where their journey had begun in May 1804.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1989</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>24</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1989, the oil tanker Exxon Valdez ran aground, spilling some 11 million gallons (41 million litres) of oil into Prince William Sound in Alaska and creating the largest oil spill in U.S. history up to that time.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1306</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>25</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Robert the Bruce, crowned Scottish king at Scone this day in 1306, freed Scotland from English rule, winning the decisive Battle of Bannockburn (1314) and confirming Scottish independence in the Treaty of Northampton (1328).</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1979</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>26</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The historic peace treaty between Israel and Egypt, agreed to by Menachem Begin and Anwar Sadat and based on the Camp David Accords mediated by U.S. President Jimmy Carter in September 1978, was signed this day in 1979.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1998</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>27</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info> The drug Viagra from the pharmaceutical company Pfizer was approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration for use in treating erectile dysfunction.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1930</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>28</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Built as Byzantium about 657 bce, then renamed Constantinople in the 4th century ce after Constantine the Great made the city his capital, the Turkish city of Istanbul officially received its present name on this day in 1930.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1867</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>29</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1867, with the British North America Act, the British colonies of Nova Scotia, New Brunswick, and Canada were united as the Dominion of Canada, and the province of Canada was separated into Quebec and Ontario.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1981</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>30</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>In Washington, D.C., on this day in 1981, barely two months after his inauguration as the 40th president of the United States, Ronald Reagan was shot and seriously wounded by would-be assassin John W. Hinckley, Jr.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1889</Year>
      <Month>3</Month>
      <Day>31</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The 984-foot (300-metre) Eiffel Tower, a wrought iron technological masterpiece created by Gustave Eiffel to commemorate the centenary of the French Revolution, was officially inaugurated in Paris this day in 1889.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1999</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>1</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Created this day in 1999 by carving a vast region from Canada's Northwest Territories, the Canadian territory of Nunavut stretches across much of the Canadian Arctic and encompasses the traditional lands of the Inuit.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2005</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>2</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Bishop of Rome and head of the Roman Catholic Church from 1978, Pope John Paul II, who was the first non-Italian pope in 455 years and the first from a Slavic country, died in Vatican City this day in 2005.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1948</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>3</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1948, U.S. President Harry S. Truman signed into law George C. Marshall's post-World War II plan to revive the economies of western and southern European countries so as to foster democracy in the region.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1968</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>4</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1968, Martin Luther King, Jr., a leader of the American civil rights movement who was in Memphis, Tennessee, to support a strike by the city's sanitation workers, was assassinated by James Earl Ray.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1818</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>5</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Chile's independence movement, led by Jos? de San Martín and Bernardo O'Higgins, won a decisive victory over Spain in the Battle of Maipú, which left 2,000 Spaniards and 1,000 Chilean patriots dead on this day in 1818.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1896</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>6</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Pierre, baron de Coubertin, a founder of the International Olympic Committee and its president from 1896 to 1925, realized his goal of reviving the Olympics when the first modern Games opened in Athens this day in 1896.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1963</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>7</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>American professional golfer Jack Nicklaus, a dominating figure in world golf from the 1960s to the '80s and the winner of 73 PGA tour events in his career, won the Masters Tournament at age 23 on this day in 1963.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1990</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>8</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info> The first episode of Twin Peaks aired on television, and it won critical acclaim and a cult following with its unconventional narrative, surreal tone, and eerie characters.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2003</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>9</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Baghdad fell to U.S.-led forces on this day in 2003, several weeks after the start of the Iraq War, a conflict begun to oust Iraqi President Saddam Hussein because of his supposed possession of weapons of mass destruction.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1938</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>10</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>In a controlled plebiscite in Austria this day in 1938, soon after Adolf Hitler's invasion of the country, 99.7 percent of Austrians approved the Anschluss (German: "Union")-the political unification of Austria and Germany.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1814</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>11</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1814, during the Napoleonic wars, Napoleon was facing an invasion of France by forces bent on his overthrow and, pressed by his own officers, abdicated unconditionally at Fontainebleau.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1981</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>12</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1981, NASA launched the first space shuttle, Columbia, which was designed to orbit Earth, transport people and cargo to and from orbiting spacecraft, and glide to a runway landing on its return to Earth.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1895</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>13</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Accused of selling military secrets to Germany and convicted in an irregular trial against a backdrop of anti-Semitism, French officer Alfred Dreyfus was imprisoned this day in 1895 on Devils Island, off French Guiana.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1865</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>14</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1865, just after the effective end of the American Civil War, U.S. President Abraham Lincoln was shot by John Wilkes Booth while attending a production at Ford's Theatre in Washington, D.C., and died the next morning.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1912</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>15</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1912, the British luxury passenger liner Titanic sank en route to New York City from Southampton, Hampshire, England, after striking an iceberg during its maiden voyage; some 1,500 people died.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1912</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>16</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1912, American aviator Harriet Quimby became the first woman to fly across the English Channel, guiding her French Bl?riot monoplane through heavy overcast from Dover, England, to Hardelot, France.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1982</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>17</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Canada Act, also known as the Constitution Act, took effect on this day in 1982, establishing certain individual rights, preserving parliamentary supremacy, and making Canada a wholly independent, fully sovereign state.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1775</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>18</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Paul Revere, a renowned silversmith, is better remembered as a folk hero of the American Revolution who this night in 1775 made a dramatic ride on horseback to warn Boston-area residents of an imminent attack by British troops.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1775</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>19</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Launched this day in 1775 with the Battles of Lexington and Concord, the American Revolution was an effort by 13 British colonies in North America (with help from France, Spain, and the Netherlands) to win their independence.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2010</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>20</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2010, an explosion occurred on the Deepwater Horizon oil rig-located in the Gulf of Mexico, some 41 miles (66 km) off the coast of Louisiana-leading to the largest oil spill in history.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2002</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>21</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>French President Jacques Chirac faced a reelection challenge on this day in 2002 from extremist Jean-Marie Le Pen in the first round of presidential voting but two weeks later handily defeated him to win a second term.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1970</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>22</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>First celebrated on this day in 1970 in the U.S., Earth Day-founded by American politician and conservationist Gaylord Anton Nelson-helped spark the environmental movement and quickly grew into an international event.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1993</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>23</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1993, after a long history of foreign rule and decades of war, the small East African country of Eritrea began three days of voting on a referendum to make official its independence from Ethiopia.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2005</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>24</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2005, Pope Benedict XVI (Joseph Ratzinger), successor to John Paul II, formally assumed his position as the new leader of the Roman Catholic Church during a mass in St. Peter's Square in Vatican City.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1990</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>25</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Hubble Space Telescope, a sophisticated optical observatory built in the United States under the supervision of NASA, was placed into operation this day in 1990 by the crew of the space shuttle Discovery.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1986</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>26</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>A devastating environmental catastrophe occurred early this morning in 1986 when an explosion and fire at the Chernobyl nuclear power plant in Ukraine released large amounts of radioactive material into the atmosphere.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1961</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>27</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Sierra Leone-which for years had been a British colony and protectorate-achieved independence within the British Commonwealth; Sir Milton Margai served as the first prime minister.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1945</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>28</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Italian dictator Benito Mussolini, "Il Duce," who, after a series of military misadventures, became unpopular even among his fellow Fascists, was captured while trying to flee Italy and was executed on this day in 1945.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2011</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>29</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2011, Prince William of Wales, second in line to the British throne, married his longtime girlfriend, Catherine Middleton, in a lavish ceremony broadcast to millions of television viewers.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1789</Year>
      <Month>4</Month>
      <Day>30</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>George Washington, the first president of the United States, was inaugurated this day in 1789 in Federal Hall in New York City, addressing his constituency on "the proceedings of a new and free government."</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1889</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>1</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1889, May Day-traditionally a celebration of the return of spring, marked by dancing around a Maypole-was first observed as a labour holiday, designated as such by the International Socialist Congress.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1939</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>2</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1939, New York Yankee great Lou Gehrig, the "Iron Horse" of American baseball, ended his streak of consecutive games played (2,130), setting a record that stood until 1995, when it was broken by Cal Ripken, Jr.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1979</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>3</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1979, Margaret Thatcher of the Conservative Party was elected British prime minister, becoming the first woman in Europe to hold that post; she later became the longest continuously serving British premier since 1827.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1970</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>4</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1970, an anti-Vietnam War demonstration at Kent State University turned deadly when the Ohio National Guard shot four unarmed students and wounded nine others, further turning public opinion against the war.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1862</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>5</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1862, Mexico repelled the French forces of Napoleon III at the Battle of Puebla, a victory that became a symbol of resistance to foreign domination and is now celebrated as a national holiday, Cinco de Mayo.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1937</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>6</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1937, while landing at Lakehurst, New Jersey, on its first transatlantic crossing of the year, the German dirigible Hindenburg burst into flames and was destroyed, killing 36 of the 97 persons aboard.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1663</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>7</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Theatre Royal, built by the dramatist Thomas Killigrew for his company of actors and now commonly known as the Drury Lane Theatre, opened in London this day in 1663 and is the oldest English theatre still in use.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1945</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>8</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Following Germany's unconditional surrender, World War II in Europe officially ended at midnight on this day in 1945, although the war in the Pacific continued until the Japanese surrender in September.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1502</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>9</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1502, master navigator and admiral Christopher Columbus, long considered the "discoverer" of the New World, set sail from Cádiz, Spain, on his fourth and final voyage, hoping to find a passage to Asia.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1994</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>10</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Nelson Mandela, whose efforts to end apartheid led to his imprisonment (1962-90) and earned him a share (with F.W. de Klerk) of the 1993 Nobel Peace Prize, became president of South Africa this day in 1994.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>330</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>11</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 330, Constantine I dedicated Byzantium (Constantinople; now Istanbul) as the new capital of the Eastern Roman Empire, an act that helped transform it into a leading city of the world.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1926</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>12</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Aboard the semirigid airship Norge, Norwegian explorer Roald Amundsen, American scientist Lincoln Ellsworth, and Italian engineer Umberto Nobile made the first undisputed flight over the North Pole on this day in 1926.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1846</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>13</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Tensions between Mexico and the United States-stemming from the U.S. annexation of Texas (1845)-led the U.S. Congress on this day in 1846 to approve overwhelmingly a declaration of war against Mexico.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1948</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>14</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1948-just before the expiry of the British mandate in Palestine-David Ben-Gurion and the Jewish People's Council proclaimed the establishment of the State of Israel, precipitating the first Arab-Israeli war.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1991</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>15</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1991, Edith Cresson of the Socialist Party became the first female premier of France, but she lost the office less than a year later because of rising unemployment and declining support from within her party.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1943</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>16</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1943, Nazi troops quelled the monthlong Warsaw Ghetto Uprising, in which Polish Jews, led by Mordecai Anielewicz and the Jewish Fighting Organization, resisted deportation to the Treblinka extermination camp.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1954</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>17</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1954, lawyer Thurgood Marshall scored a landmark victory as the U.S. Supreme Court unanimously ruled in Brown v. Board of Education of Topeka that racial segregation in public schools was unconstitutional.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1980</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>18</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1980, following an earthquake with a magnitude of 5.1 on the Richter scale, Mount St. Helens in Washington state erupted in one of the greatest volcanic explosions ever recorded in North America.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1884</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>19</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Ringling brothers opened a small circus in Baraboo, Wisconsin, on this day in 1884 and by the early 20th century had transformed it into the Ringling Bros. and Barnum &amp; Bailey Circus, the leading American circus.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1862</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>20</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1862, U.S. President Abraham Lincoln signed the Homestead Act, which provided 160 acres of public land virtually free of charge to those who had lived on and cultivated the land for at least five years.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1927</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>21</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>American aviator Charles Lindbergh completed the first nonstop solo flight across the Atlantic Ocean on this day in 1927, traveling from New York to Paris in the monoplane Spirit of Saint Louis in about 33.5 hours.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>337</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>22</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 337, Constantine the Great, who had practiced Christianity since his youth and sparked its growth into a world religion, became on his deathbed the first Roman emperor to be baptized in the Christian church.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1951</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>23</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>China formally annexed Tibet as an autonomous region on this day in 1951, giving rise to a Tibetan independence movement-led by the Dalai Lama, winner of the 1989 Nobel Peace Prize-that continued into the early 21st century.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1883</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>24</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>A brilliant feat of 19th-century engineering, the Brooklyn Bridge-spanning the East River from Brooklyn to Manhattan Island in New York City-opened this day in 1883, designed by civil engineer John Augustus Roebling.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1787</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>25</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1787, the Constitutional Convention opened in Philadelphia, where 55 state delegates, initially charged with amending the Articles of Confederation, later drafted the Constitution of the United States.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1521</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>26</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Passed this day in 1521, the Edict of Worms banned the writings of Martin Luther-a German cleric whose efforts to change the church led to the Reformation-and declared him an outlaw and a heretic who was to be captured.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1703</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>27</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Founded this day in 1703 by Peter the Great, St. Petersburg has played a vital role in Russian history and is especially known as the scene of the 1917 revolutions and as a fiercely defended city during World War II.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1961</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>28</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Dedicated to informing public opinion about human rights and to securing the release of political prisoners, Amnesty International was founded in London on this day in 1961 and won the 1977 Nobel Peace Prize.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1953</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>29</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Following numerous failed attempts by others, Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay became the first climbers to surmount Mount Everest, the highest mountain in the world (29,032 feet [8,849 metres]), on this day in 1953.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1431</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>30</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Having led the French army in a momentous victory over England at Orl?ans during the Hundred Years' War, Joan of Arc was charged with heresy and witchcraft and, on this day in 1431, was burned at the stake.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1962</Year>
      <Month>5</Month>
      <Day>31</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1962, the State of Israel hanged German official Adolf Eichmann, who had escaped from a prison camp in 1946 and spent some 14 years in hiding, for his part in the Nazi extermination of Jews during World War II.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1980</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>1</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Ted Turner's Cable News Network (CNN), headquartered in Atlanta, began 24-hour live news broadcasts this day in 1980 and gained worldwide attention in 1991 for its around-the-clock coverage of the Persian Gulf War</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1953</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>2</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1953, 27-year-old Elizabeth II, the elder daughter of King George VI, was crowned queen of the United Kingdom at Westminster Abbey, having taken the throne upon her father's death in February 1952.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1989</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>3</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1989, the Chinese government called in the military to put down a pro-democracy demonstration staged by more than 100,000 people in Tiananmen Square in Beijing, resulting in hundreds of deaths.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1940</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>4</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Following a massive rescue effort that included civilian boats, the withdrawal of Allied troops trapped at Dunkirk, France, was completed on this day during World War II; more than 300,000 soldiers were saved.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1967</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>5</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Israel-amid rising tensions with Egypt, Syria, and Jordan-staged a preemptive air assault and soundly defeated those Arab countries, notably seizing the Old City of Jerusalem and the Gaza Strip before a cease-fire.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1944</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>6</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Led by U.S. General Dwight D. Eisenhower, an Allied armada of ships, planes, and landing craft and some 156,000 troops began the invasion of northern France from England this day in 1944-the famous "D-Day" of World War II.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1929</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>7</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Through the Lateran Treaty-signed February 11, 1929, by Benito Mussolini for Italy and by Pietro Gasparri, cardinal secretary of state, for the papacy and ratified this day in 1929-Vatican City became a sovereign state.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1504</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>8</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Believed to have been installed this day in 1504 in the cathedral of Florence was Michelangelo's statue of David, commissioned in 1501 and considered the prime statement of the Renaissance ideal of perfect humanity.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1983</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>9</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>British Conservative Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher, buoyed by victory in the Falkland Islands War and by deep divisions within the opposition Labour Party, was easily reelected to a second term in office this day in 1983.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1692</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>10</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Being found guilty of "certaine Detestable Arts called Witchcraft and Sorceries," Bridget Bishop on this day in 1692 became the first person to be hanged during the Salem witch trials in the Massachusetts Bay Colony.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2001</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>11</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Timothy McVeigh-convicted of the bombing of a federal building in Oklahoma City on April 19, 1995, which killed 168 people in what was then the worst terrorist attack in the U.S.-was executed this day in 2001.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1991</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>12</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1991, Boris Yeltsin was easily elected president of Russia (then part of the Soviet Union) in the republic's first direct, popular elections, and he was president of independent Russia until the eve of 2000.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2000</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>13</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2000, South Korean President Kim Dae-Jung met North Korean leader Kim Jong Il in a summit that marked the first meeting between heads of the two countries, helping earn Kim Dae-Jung the Nobel Peace Prize.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1940</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>14</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1940, the first transport of Polish political prisoners arrived at Auschwitz, which became Nazi Germany's largest concentration, extermination, and slave-labour camp, where more than one million people died.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1215</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>15</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Magna Carta-a charter of English liberties that occupies a unique place in the popular imagination as a symbol and a battle cry against oppression-was sealed this day, under threat of civil war, by King John in 1215.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1963</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>16</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1963, Soviet cosmonaut Valentina V. Tereshkova became the first woman to travel in space, having been launched into orbit aboard the spacecraft Vostok 6, which completed 48 orbits in 71 hours.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1994</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>17</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1994, American gridiron football hero O.J. Simpson was charged with the murders of his ex-wife Nicole Simpson and her friend Ronald Goldman, though after a sensational trial he was acquitted the following year.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1812</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>18</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day U.S. President James Madison signed a declaration of war against Great Britain, initiating the War of 1812, which arose chiefly from U.S. grievances over oppressive maritime practices during the Napoleonic Wars.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1953</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>19</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>After the failure of court appeals and of a worldwide campaign for mercy, husband and wife Julius and Ethel Rosenberg were put to death this day in 1953, becoming the first American civilians to be executed for espionage.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1567</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>20</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Casket Letters-which directly implicated Mary, Queen of Scots, in a plot with James Hepburn, 4th earl of Bothwell, to murder Mary's husband, Henry Stewart, Lord Darnley-were said to have been discovered this day in 1567.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1945</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>21</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Japanese resistance on Okinawa was finally crushed this day in 1945, less than three months after U.S. troops landed there as the last stepping-stone before the planned assault on Japan's main islands in World War II.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1611</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>22</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1611, English explorer Henry Hudson-who earlier had tried to discover a short route from Europe to Asia through the Arctic Ocean-was set adrift with his son and seven others in Hudson Bay by mutineers.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1314</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>23</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1314 began the Battle of Bannockburn, a decisive engagement in Scottish history whereby the Scots defeated the English, regained their independence, and established Robert the Bruce as Robert I.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1812</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>24</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1812, French Emperor Napoleon-who had massed his troops in Poland in the spring to intimidate Russian Tsar Alexander I-and 600,000 troops of his Grand Army launched an ill-fated invasion of Russia.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1950</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>25</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1950, North Korea unleashed an attack southward across the 38th parallel, after which the UN Security Council (minus the Soviet delegate) passed a resolution calling on UN members to assist South Korea.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1976</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>26</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>CN Tower, which opened to the public this day in 1976, was-at 1,815 feet (553 metres)-the world's tallest freestanding structure until being surpassed in 2007 by the Burj Khalifa in Dubai, United Arab Emirates.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1871</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>27</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>First minted in 1869, the yen was adopted as Japan's official monetary unit this day in 1871, when the government suspended the exchange of clan notes, money issued by feudal lords that had circulated since the 16th century.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1914</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>28</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1914, Archduke Franz Ferdinand, heir to the Austro-Hungarian throne, and his consort, Sophie, were assassinated by Gavrilo Princip in Sarajevo, Bosnia, precipitating the outbreak of World War I.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1613</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>29</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>During a performance of William Shakespeare's Henry VIII on this day in 1613, the Globe Theatre was destroyed within an hour after its thatch was accidentally set aflame by a cannon marking the king's entrance onstage.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1934</Year>
      <Month>6</Month>
      <Day>30</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this date in 1934 occurred the "Night of the Long Knives," in which German dictator Adolf Hitler had his elite SS guards summarily execute many leading officials of the SA, a Nazi paramilitary group.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1867</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>1</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Dominion of Canada was formed this day in 1867, an event subsequently celebrated as an annual Canadian holiday (its current name, Canada Day, was adopted in 1982) marked by parades, fireworks, and the display of flags.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1964</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>2</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1964, U.S. President Lyndon B. Johnson signed the Civil Rights Act, perhaps the most important U.S. law on civil rights since Reconstruction (1865-77) and a hallmark of the American civil rights movement.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1863</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>3</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Following three days of intense fighting-casualties numbered more than 50,000-the Battle of Gettysburg ended on this day in 1863 with a victory for the Union forces and was seen as a turning point in the American Civil War.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1776</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>4</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Declaration of Independence, adopted this day in 1776 by the Second Continental Congress, called for the American colonies to secede from Great Britain, a proclamation now commemorated by a U.S. national holiday.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1950</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>5</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Passed this day in 1950 by the Knesset, the Law of Return granted Jews the freedom to immigrate to Israel and receive immediate citizenship, but it proved controversial when the question "Who is a Jew?" raised other issues.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1942</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>6</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Anne Frank and her family went into hiding in Amsterdam on this day in 1942 and lived in a secret annex-an experience documented in her diary, which became a classic of war literature-until their capture on August 4, 1944.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1898</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>7</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The U.S. Congress annexed Hawaii through a joint resolution signed by President William McKinley on this day in 1898, paving the way for the islands to become a territory (1900) and later a U.S. state (1959).</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1497</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>8</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1497, Vasco da Gama sailed from Lisbon with a fleet of four vessels, and he ultimately opened a sea route from western Europe to Asia by way of the Cape of Good Hope, ushering in a new era in world history.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1762</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>9</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Catherine the Great overthrew Peter III on this day in 1762 and began her reign as empress of Russia, leading her country into full participation in the political and cultural life of Europe and extending Russian territory.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1962</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>10</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Telstar 1, the first communications satellite to transmit live television signals and telephone conversations across the Atlantic Ocean, was launched this day in 1962, inaugurating a new age in electronic communications.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1804</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>11</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Outraged over disparaging remarks that Alexander Hamilton had allegedly made at a dinner party, Aaron Burr challenged his longtime rival to a duel, and on this day in 1804 he fatally shot Hamilton in Weehawken, New Jersey.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1984</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>12</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Democratic presidential candidate Walter F. Mondale put forward Geraldine Ferraro as his running mate on this day in 1984, making her the first woman ever nominated for vice president by a major U.S. political party.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1793</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>13</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1793, Jean-Paul Marat, a leader of the radical Montagnard faction during the French Revolution, was stabbed to death in his bath by Charlotte Corday, a young Girondin supporter who was subsequently guillotined.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1789</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>14</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1789, a mob advanced on the Bastille in Paris, demanding the arms and munitions stored there, but, when the guards resisted, the crowd captured the prison, an act that symbolized the end of the ancien r?gime.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1964</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>15</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Mariner 4, an uncrewed space probe launched by NASA in 1964, flew by Mars and returned close-up pictures of its surface on this day in 1965, the pictures proving that the planet's rumoured canals were actually illusions.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1945</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>16</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The United States tested the first atomic bomb this day in 1945 near Alamogordo, New Mexico, and the following month dropped atomic bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki in Japan, hastening the end of World War II.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1936</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>17</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>A well-planned uprising by Nationalist rebels against the Republican government of Spain began this day in 1936, sparking a bloody civil war that lasted until 1939, when the Nationalists and Francisco Franco assumed power.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1925</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>18</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The first volume of Mein Kampf, the political manifesto written by Adolf Hitler that became the bible of Nazism in Germany's Third Reich, was published this day in 1925, and two years later the second volume appeared.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1848</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>19</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1848, the women's suffrage movement in the United States was launched with the opening of the Seneca Falls Convention, which sought to gain certain rights and privileges for women, notably the right to vote.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1969</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>20</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1969, the Eagle lunar landing module, carrying U.S. astronauts Neil Armstrong and Edwin ("Buzz") Aldrin, landed on the Moon, and several hours later Armstrong became the first person to set foot on its surface.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1798</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>21</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Napoleon's Army of Egypt used a new military tactic, the massive divisional square, to defeat the Egyptian forces of Murad Bey this day in 1798 at the Battle of the Pyramids during Napoleon's Egyptian campaign.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1977</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>22</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>After falling from favour during the Cultural Revolution (1966-76), Deng Xiaoping returned to power on this day in 1977 after the Chinese Communist Party reinstated all his former high posts, including that of vice-premier.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1952</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>23</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1952, the Free Officers, a nationalistic military group led by Colonel Gamal Abdel Nasser, engineered a coup that overthrew King Farouk I of Egypt, ending the monarchy and bringing Nasser to power.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1917</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>24</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Dutch-born dancer and courtesan Mata Hari, whose name became a synonym for the seductive female spy, went on trial this day in 1917, accused of spying for Germany, and was subsequently found guilty and shot by a firing squad.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1814</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>25</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Near Niagara Falls on this day in 1814, British troops commanded by General Phineas Riall thwarted an invasion of Canada by a U.S. force under General Jacob Brown in the Battle of Lundy's Lane during the War of 1812.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1956</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>26</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1956, Egyptian President Gamal Abdel Nasser seized control of the Suez Canal and nationalized it, sparking a crisis that later resulted in French, British, and Israeli forces briefly occupying parts of Egypt.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1996</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>27</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1996 a pipe bomb exploded in Olympic Centennial Park in Atlanta, Georgia, killing 1 person and injuring 111 in the first terrorist attack at the Olympics since the 1972 Games in Munich, West Germany.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1914</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>28</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Using the assassination of the Austrian archduke Francis Ferdinand as a pretext to present Serbia with an unacceptable ultimatum, Austria-Hungary declared war on the Slavic country on this day in 1914, sparking World War I.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1958</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>29</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Criticized for allowing the Soviet Union to launch the first man-made satellite to orbit Earth (Sputnik 1, on October 4, 1957), U.S. President Dwight D. Eisenhower signed legislation this day in 1958 that created NASA.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1898</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>30</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Otto von Bismarck-who, as prime minister of Prussia (1862-73, 1873-90), used ruthlessness and moderation to unify Germany, founding the German Empire (1871) and serving as its first chancellor (1871-90)-died this day in 1898.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1971</Year>
      <Month>7</Month>
      <Day>31</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1971, Apollo 15 astronauts James B. Irwin and David Scott first used the four-wheeled battery-powered Lunar Roving Vehicle to extensively explore the Moon's surface, in particular the Hadley-Apennine site.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1589</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>1</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>King Henry III of France was stabbed this day in 1589 by Jacques Cl?ment, a Jacobin friar, and died the next day after acknowledging his Bourbon ally, Henry of Navarre (Henry IV), a Huguenot, as his successor.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1990</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>2</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Iraq invaded Kuwait on this day in 1990, and Saddam Hussein's subsequent refusal to withdraw his troops sparked the Persian Gulf War, in which an international force led by the United States quickly defeated Iraq.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1492</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>3</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Hoping to find a westward route to India, Christopher Columbus on this day in 1492 set sail on his first transatlantic voyage, departing from Palos, Spain, with three small ships-the Niña, Pinta, and Santa María.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1704</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>4</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>During the War of the Spanish Succession, Britain took control of Gibraltar on this day in 1704 after Spain surrendered, and "the Rock" subsequently became a British colony and a symbol of British naval strength.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1960</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>5</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Upper Volta-now Burkina Faso (which means "Land of Incorruptible People"), a landlocked country in western Africa-proclaimed its independence on this day in 1960, ending more than 60 years of French rule.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1945</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>6</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1945, the United States dropped an atomic bomb on Hiroshima, Japan-the blast killed more than 70,000 people and destroyed most of the city-in an effort to hasten the end of World War II.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1942</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>7</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>In the Allies' first major offensive in the Pacific theatre during World War II, U.S. Marines on this day in 1942 landed on Guadalcanal and captured the airfield from Japan, sparking a battle that lasted some six months.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1974</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>8</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Faced with the near-certain prospect of impeachment for his role in the Watergate scandal, U.S. President Richard M. Nixon announced his resignation on this day in 1974 and was succeeded by Gerald Ford the following day.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1945</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>9</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info> The second atomic bomb dropped on Japan by the United States in World War II struck the city of Nagasaki.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1792</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>10</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>As the French Revolution (1787-99) continued, the country's monarchy was effectively overthrown on this day in 1792 when King Louis XVI and his wife, Marie-Antoinette, were imprisoned (they were eventually guillotined).</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1956</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>11</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>American painter Jackson Pollock, a leading exponent of Abstract Expressionism who received great fame and serious recognition for his radical poured, or "drip," technique, died this day in 1956 in an automobile accident.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1877</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>12</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1877, American inventor Thomas Alva Edison made perhaps his most original discovery, the phonograph, and his early recordings were indentations embossed into a sheet of tinfoil by a vibrating stylus.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1521</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>13</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1521, Spanish conquistador Hernán Cort?s captured Tenochtitlán (now Mexico City) after a 93-day siege, thereby ending the Aztec empire and winning Mexico for the crown of Spain.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1248</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>14</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Originally started in 1248, construction of the cathedral (K?lner Dom) in Cologne, Germany-the largest Gothic church in northern Europe and the city's major landmark-was finally completed on this day in 1880.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1947</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>15</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>After three decades, the Indian independence movement, led by Mahatma Gandhi, achieved its goal on this day in 1947 as a free and independent India was established, ending nearly 200 years of British rule.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1996</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>16</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The youngest person ever elected president of the Dominican Republic, Leonel Fernández Reyna was sworn in this day in 1996 and soon instituted measures to end corruption and to improve the country's economy.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1945</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>17</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1945, Sukarno declared Indonesia's independence from the Netherlands, and, after the Dutch transferred sovereignty four years later, he served as the country's first president (1949-67).</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1920</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>18</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1920, the Nineteenth Amendment was ratified after Tennessee-by just one vote-became the 36th state to approve it, capping the 72-year fight to win women the right to vote in the United States.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1991</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>19</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1991, Mikhail Gorbachev, the general secretary of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union (1985-91) and president of the Soviet Union (1990-91), was briefly ousted in a coup by communist hard-liners.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1975</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>20</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The robotic U.S. spacecraft Viking 1, built to explore the surface of Mars, was launched this day in 1975 and nearly one year later landed on Chryse Planitia, a flat lowland region in the northern hemisphere of the planet.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1911</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>21</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1911 Leonardo da Vinci's Mona Lisa was stolen from the Louvre by three Italian handymen; it was not recovered until 1913, and the media sensation helped make it one of the world's most famous paintings.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1485</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>22</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Henry Tudor (the future Henry VII) defeated the Yorkist king Richard III in the Battle of Bosworth Field on this day in 1485, effectively ending the Wars of the Roses and establishing the Tudor dynasty on the English throne.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1305</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>23</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in London, William Wallace was executed for treason, condemned for leading Scottish resistance forces during the first years of the long and ultimately successful struggle to free Scotland from English rule.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>79</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>24</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Mount Vesuvius in Italy erupted on this day in 79 ce, destroying the ancient cities of Pompeii and Herculaneum, and the excavations of these sites in the mid-18th century precipitated the modern science of archaeology.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1944</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>25</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1944, some two months after the Allied invasion of Normandy, Paris was liberated from German occupiers as the Free French 2nd Armoured Division under General Jacques-Philippe Leclerc entered the city.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1429</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>26</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>In preparation for an attack on Paris, part of Charles VII's campaign to drive the English from French soil, Joan of Arc and her soldiers reached the city's outskirts on this day in 1429, but the assault ultimately failed.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1576</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>27</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Titian, the greatest Italian Renaissance painter of the Venetian school, who was once described as "the sun amidst small stars not only among the Italians but all the painters of the world," died this day in 1576.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1963</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>28</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1963, some 200,000 people marched on Washington, D.C., an event that became a high point of the civil rights movement, especially remembered for the famous "I Have a Dream" speech of Martin Luther King, Jr.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2005</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>29</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2005, Hurricane Katrina struck the U.S. Gulf Coast and devastated the area, especially New Orleans, which experienced catastrophic flooding after its levees were breached the following day.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1983</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>30</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>U.S. astronaut Guion S. Bluford, Jr., became on this day in 1983 the first African American to travel into space, serving as a mission specialist aboard the shuttle orbiter Challenger, and later flew on three other missions.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1864</Year>
      <Month>8</Month>
      <Day>31</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>During the American Civil War, the Confederate evacuation of Atlanta began this day in 1864, shortly before Union troops led by William Tecumseh Sherman occupied the city, providing a much-needed victory for the North.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1939</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>1</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The lethal combination of German blitzkrieg tactics, French and British inactivity, and Soviet perfidy doomed Poland to swift defeat after Adolf Hitler invaded the country this day in 1939 and sparked World War II.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1666</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>2</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1666 the Great Fire of London began accidentally in the house of the king's baker; it burned for four days and destroyed a large part of the city, including Old St. Paul's Cathedral and about 13,000 houses.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1976</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>3</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>After a nearly yearlong journey, NASA's robotic spacecraft Viking 2 landed on Mars this day in 1976 and began relaying information about the planet's atmosphere and soil as well as colour photographs of the rocky surface.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1781</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>4</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1781, Spanish settlers laid claim to what became Los Angeles, now the second most populous U.S. city and the home to Hollywood, whose name is synonymous with the American motion-picture industry.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2001</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>5</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>At a scientific conference in Washington, D.C., this day in 2001, scientists described an observation of energy flares that provided strong evidence of the theorized black hole at the centre of the Milky Way Galaxy.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1901</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>6</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Republican William McKinley, the 25th president of the United States (1897-1901), was shot this day in 1901 by Leon Czolgosz, an anarchist, at the Pan-American Exposition in Buffalo, New York, and died eight days later.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1191</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>7</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1191 the Muslim army of Saladin attacked the Crusaders of Richard I (the Lion-Heart) at the Battle of Arsuf, and, though Richard successfully counterattacked in the evening, his march to Jerusalem was delayed.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1429</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>8</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1429, French heroine Joan of Arc, a peasant girl who believed she was acting under divine guidance, attempted to oust the duke of Burgundy and take Paris for newly crowned King Charles VII.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1976</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>9</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Marxist revolutionary Mao Zedong, who died this day in 1976, emerged as the undisputed Chinese Communist Party leader following the Long March (1934-35) and dominated China in the period after the communist takeover in 1949.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1608</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>10</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Having survived capture by Indians (reputedly through the efforts of Pocahontas, a chief's daughter), John Smith became president of Jamestown colony, the first permanent English settlement in North America, this day in 1608.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2001</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>11</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2001, 19 militants associated with the terrorist group al-Qaeda hijacked four planes in the United States, crashing three into buildings (the fourth crashed in Pennsylvania) and killing some 3,000 people.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1764</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>12</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>French composer of the late Baroque period Jean-Philippe Rameau-known for his harpsichord music and famous as a composer of operas, including the masterpiece Pygmalion (1748)-died on this day in 1764.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1598</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>13</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>King Philip III of Spain (Philip II of Portugal), crowned on this day in 1598, was virtuous in his private affairs but indifferent as a ruler and extravagant in his spending, exacerbating Spain's growing economic problems.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1847</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>14</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>U.S. General Winfield Scott's advance on Mexico City was marked by an unbroken series of victories that culminated this day in 1847, when he entered Mexico City and ended the military phase of the Mexican-American War.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1821</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>15</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1821, Central American notables accepted a plan drafted by the Mexican caudillo Agustín de Iturbide that brought independence from Spain to Costa Rica, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras, and Nicaragua.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1620</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>16</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this date in 1620, English colonists aboard the Mayflower set sail for America, where they founded Plymouth, Massachusetts, after 41 men, including William Bradford and Myles Standish, signed the Mayflower Compact.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1978</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>17</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Camp David Accords, negotiated by U.S. President Jimmy Carter, were completed this day in 1978, leading to a peace treaty between Egypt and Israel and a broader framework for pursuing peace in the Middle East.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1931</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>18</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1931, in the so-called Mukden Incident, the Japanese army in Manchuria used the pretext of an explosion along its railway to occupy Mukden and to increase its control, within three months, to all of Manchuria.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1796</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>19</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>In his Farewell Address, printed in a Philadelphia newspaper on this day in 1796, George Washington, the first U.S. president, implored his country to maintain neutrality and avoid entangling alliances with Europe.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1870</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>20</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1870, Italian troops occupied Rome, leading to the eventual incorporation of Rome into the Kingdom of Italy and the limiting of papal governing authority to the Vatican itself and a small district around it.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1823</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>21</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>According to the teachings of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, Moroni was an angel or resurrected being who appeared to Joseph Smith on this day in 1823 and instructed him to restore God's church on earth.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1980</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>22</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Solidarity, the Polish trade union and political party that became a hotbed of resistance to Soviet control, was founded this day in 1980 when delegates of 36 unions met and united under the leadership of Lech Walesa.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1846</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>23</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>This day in 1846, astronomer Johann Gottfried Galle became the first person ever to observe the planet Neptune, the existence of which had been mathematically predicted by Urbain-Jean-Joseph Le Verrier and John Couch Adams.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1957</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>24</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1957 racial desegregation took centre stage when federal troops were dispatched to Little Rock, Arkansas, to maintain order and enforce the right of black students to attend the local public high school.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1513</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>25</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day (or two days later) in 1513, Spanish conquistador and explorer Vasco Núñez de Balboa, standing "silent, upon a peak in Dari?n," on the Isthmus of Panama, became the first European to sight the Pacific Ocean.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1960</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>26</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The first in a series of historic televised debates (seen by some 85 to 120 million viewers) between U.S. presidential candidates John F. Kennedy and Vice President Richard M. Nixon was broadcast this day in 1960.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1066</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>27</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1066, after being delayed by bad weather, William, duke of Normandy, embarked his army and set sail for the southeastern coast of England in what would be known in history as the Norman Conquest.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1542</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>28</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Explorer Juan Rodríguez Cabrillo, known as the "discoverer" of California, landed this day in 1542 near what is now San Diego and became the first European to set foot on the west coast of what would become the United States.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1923</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>29</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Set in motion by the Balfour Declaration of 1917, the British mandate for the establishment of a Jewish homeland in Palestine was finally approved by the Council of the League of Nations and came into force this day in 1923.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1938</Year>
      <Month>9</Month>
      <Day>30</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The notorious Munich Agreement, in which Britain's Neville Chamberlain encouraged Britain and France to appease Adolf Hitler's demands in the hope of preventing World War II, was reached on this day in 1938.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1949</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>1</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>In Beijing, with most of the Chinese mainland held by the communist People's Liberation Army, its dynamic leader, Mao Zedong, proclaimed the establishment of the People's Republic of China on this day in 1949.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1836</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>2</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Naturalist Charles Darwin returned to England this day in 1836 after a five-year journey on the HMS Beagle, on which he gathered the specimens and observations that led to his theory of evolution by natural selection.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1990</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>3</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>After four decades of Cold War division and with pressure from the German chancellor Helmut Kohl, Soviet leader Mikhail Gorbachev agreed to a unified Germany within NATO, leading to Germany's reunification this day in 1990.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1957</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>4</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1957 the Soviet Union launched Sputnik 1, the first artificial satellite, which orbited Earth until 1958, inaugurated the space age, and heightened Cold War competition between the U.S.S.R. and the U.S.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1813</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>5</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1813, during the War of 1812, a British army with some 1,000 Indian allies under the famed leader Tecumseh was defeated by U.S. troops in the Battle of the Thames in what is now Ontario, Canada.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1973</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>6</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1973, on the Jewish holy day of Yom Kippur, Egypt and Syria attacked Israel, which suffered heavy casualties, but Israeli forces successfully fought back, and the war eventually ended inconclusively.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1949</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>7</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1949, a constitution went into effect in the Soviet occupation zone of Germany that formed the country of East Germany, which existed alongside West Germany until 1990, when the two Germanys reunited.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1871</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>8</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1871, the Great Chicago Fire began in the barn of Patrick and Catherine O'Leary, and, by the time the blaze died out two days later, a large swath of the city had been devastated and some 300 people killed.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2004</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>9</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2004, for the first time in Afghanistan's history, voters went to the polls to choose a president, selecting Hamid Karzai, who had served as the interim president after the fall of the Taliban regime in 2001.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1845</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>10</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>To improve the then-unsatisfactory methods of instructing midshipmen, George Bancroft-historian, educator, and secretary of the navy-founded the U.S. Naval Academy in Annapolis, Maryland, on this day in 1845.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1962</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>11</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Second Vatican Council, announced by Pope John XXIII in 1959, opened this day in 1962, lasted for three years, and remains a symbol (controversial to some) of the church's readiness to adapt to modern life.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1492</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>12</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The New World was "discovered" this day in 1492 when land (most likely San Salvador) was sighted in the Caribbean from the Pinta, one of the three ships that participated in Christopher Columbus's historic voyage.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1792</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>13</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The cornerstone for the White House, the official office and home of every U.S. president and first lady since 1800 (when John and Abigail Adams moved in near the end of his term), was laid this day in 1792.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1066</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>14</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>At the Battle of Hastings, fought this day in 1066, King Harold II of England was defeated by the invading army of William, duke of Normandy, in the Norman Conquest, establishing Normans as rulers of England.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1959</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>15</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1959 a final conference on the Antarctic Treaty convened in Washington, D.C., and, after six weeks of negotiations, the treaty was signed by 12 countries, preserving the continent for free scientific study.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1793</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>16</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>After the French Revolution began, Marie-Antoinette, queen consort of Louis XVI, was targeted by agitators who, enraged by her extravagance and attempts to save the monarchy, ultimately guillotined her on this day in 1793.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1979</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>17</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1979, Mother Teresa, founder of a Roman Catholic order of women dedicated to the poor and particularly to the destitute of India, was named the recipient of that year's Nobel Prize for Peace.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1867</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>18</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>After much opposition, a deal negotiated by U.S. Secretary of State William Seward for the U.S. purchase of the Russian colony of Alaska was approved, and on this day in 1867 the U.S. flag was flown over the capital, Sitka.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1781</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>19</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1781, Britain's Lord Cornwallis surrendered at Yorktown, Virginia, handing a huge victory to American General George Washington and effectively ending the American Revolution and assuring America's independence.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1973</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>20</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Australia's Sydney Opera House-designed by Danish architect Jorn Utzon, whose dynamic, imaginative, but problematic plan won an international competition in 1957-was opened by Queen Elizabeth II on this day in 1973.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1520</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>21</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1520, explorer Ferdinand Magellan and three Spanish ships entered the strait later named for him, sailing between the mainland tip of South America and the island of Tierra del Fuego toward the Pacific Ocean.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1962</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>22</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1962, President John F. Kennedy alerted Americans to the Cuban missile crisis, declaring a naval blockade to prevent further missile shipments to the island country 90 miles (145 km) off the coast of the U.S.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1983</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>23</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1983, suicide bombers drove truckloads of high explosives into the barracks of U.S. Marines and French paratroopers in Beirut, killing 241 U.S. servicemen and 58 French troops.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1945</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>24</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The charter for the United Nations-the world's premier international organization, established at the end of World War II to maintain world peace and friendly relations among nations-entered into force this day in 1945.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1415</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>25</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1415, the English army, led by Henry V, scored a decisive victory over the French at the Battle of Agincourt during the Hundred Years' War, paving the way for further English conquests and successes.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1979</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>26</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1979, South Korean President Park Chung Hee was assassinated by his lifelong friend Kim Jae Kyu, head of the Korean Central Intelligence Agency, who was sentenced to death for his actions.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1978</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>27</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1978, Anwar Sadat of Egypt and Menachem Begin of Israel were awarded the Nobel Prize for Peace for negotiations that resulted first in the Camp David Accords, then in a peace treaty between their countries.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1886</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>28</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1886 U.S. President Grover Cleveland officially dedicated the Statue of Liberty-a gift from the people of France to the people of the United States-on Bedloe's (later Liberty) Island in Upper New York Bay.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1929</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>29</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Just five days after nearly 13 million shares of U.S. stock were sold in one day in 1929, an additional 16 million shares were sold this day, called "Black Tuesday," further fueling the crisis known as the Great Depression.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1485</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>30</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Henry Tudor, who was crowned Henry VII on this day in 1485, founded the Tudor dynasty, ended the Wars of the Roses, used his children's marriages to build alliances, and signed treaties that increased England's power.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1517</Year>
      <Month>10</Month>
      <Day>31</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>According to tradition, Martin Luther this day in 1517 posted on a church door in Wittenberg, Germany, his Ninety-five Theses, a manifesto that turned a protest about an indulgence scandal into the Protestant Reformation.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1952</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>1</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1952 on an atoll of the Marshall Islands, Edward Teller and other American scientists tested the first thermonuclear bomb, its power resulting from an uncontrolled, self-sustaining nuclear chain reaction.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1976</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>2</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Jimmy Carter, recipient of the Nobel Prize for Peace in 2002 and Democratic former governor of Georgia, was elected 39th president of the United States this day in 1976, narrowly defeating Republican Gerald R. Ford.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1998</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>3</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Announced on this day in 1998 was the discovery in the Hui Autonomous Region of Ningxia of a previously unknown 15.5-mile (25-km) segment of the Great Wall of China, which runs a total of about 4,500 miles (7,300 km).</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1995</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>4</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Israeli Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin, corecipient with Shimon Peres and Yasir ?Arafat of the Nobel Prize for Peace in 1994, was assassinated this day in 1995 by a Jewish extremist while attending a peace rally.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1605</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>5</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Celebrated with fireworks as Guy Fawkes Day, this English holiday marks the anniversary of the Gunpowder Plot, when Roman Catholics led by Robert Catesby tried to blow up Parliament, the king, and his family this day in 1605.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1860</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>6</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1860, Americans elected as their president Abraham Lincoln, whose victory led to the secession of Southern states and the long and bloody Civil War that lasted until 1865 and ended slavery in the U.S.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2000</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>7</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2000, the U.S. presidential election ended in a statistical tie between Democrat Al Gore and Republican George W. Bush, only to be settled on December 12 by the U.S. Supreme Court after a bitter legal dispute.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2013</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>8</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2013, the Philippines endured what many consider its worst natural disaster when the country was struck by Super Typhoon Haiyan, one of the most powerful cyclones ever recorded to strike land.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1989</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>9</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Long a symbol of the Cold War, the Berlin Wall, erected in 1961 and eventually extending 28 miles (45 km) to divide the western and eastern sectors of Berlin, was opened by the East German government on this day in 1989.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1871</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>10</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1871, according to his journal, explorer Henry Stanley greeted David Livingstone, the fellow explorer in search of the source of the Nile River, with the famous words "Dr. Livingstone, I presume?"</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1918</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>11</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>At 5:00 am on this day in 1918, the Allied powers and Germany signed an armistice document in the railway carriage of Ferdinand Foch, the commander of the Allied armies, and six hours later World War I came to an end.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1990</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>12</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Japanese Emperor Akihito-according to tradition, the 125th direct descendant of Jimmu, Japan's legendary first emperor-was formally enthroned on this day in 1990, nearly two years after the death of his father, Hirohito.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2015</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>13</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2015, terrorists staged coordinated attacks in Paris and its environs, the deadliest occurring at the Bataclan theatre and concert hall; in all, at least 130 people were killed and more than 350 were wounded.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1962</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>14</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1962, the Ethiopian parliament and Eritrean Assembly voted unanimously for the abolition of Eritrea's federal status, making Eritrea (independent since 1993) a simple province of the Ethiopian empire.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1988</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>15</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Meeting at Algiers, the Palestine National Council, at the urging of PLO chairman Yasser Arafat, issued a declaration of independence for a state of Palestine in the West Bank and Gaza Strip on this day in 1988.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1988</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>16</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Benazir Bhutto, elected prime minister of Pakistan on this day in 1988, became the first woman in modern history to lead a Muslim country, serving as prime minister from 1988 to 1990 and again from 1993 to 1996.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2003</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>17</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Republican Arnold Schwarzenegger, an Austrian-born American bodybuilder and film actor, was inaugurated on this day in 2003 as the governor of California following a recall election that ousted the sitting governor.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1978</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>18</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Jim Jones, leader of the Peoples Temple religious community that he formed in the 1950s, and some 900 of his followers died this day in 1978 in Guyana in a massive act of murder-suicide known as the Jonestown massacre.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1977</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>19</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>After the Arab-Israeli war of 1973-74, Egyptian President Anwar Sadat began to work toward peace, and on this day in 1977 he began his historic visit to Israel, during which he offered a peace plan to its parliament.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1910</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>20</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1910, Francisco Madero launched a failed revolt that nonetheless sparked the Mexican Revolution by inspiring hope in such leaders as Pancho Villa and Emiliano Zapata, who then mobilized their ragged armies.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1620</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>21</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1620, 41 male passengers on the Mayflower, prior to landing at Plymouth, Massachusetts, signed the Mayflower Compact, by which they agreed to abide by the laws of the new government they would establish.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1963</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>22</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The most notorious political murder in recent American history occurred this day in 1963, when John F. Kennedy, the 35th U.S. president (1961-63), was shot and killed in Dallas, Texas, while riding in an open car.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1855</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>23</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Passed this day in 1855 in Mexico, the Ley Juárez abolished special courts for the clergy and military in an attempt by justice minister Benito Juárez to eliminate the remnants of colonialism in Mexico and promote equality.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1642</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>24</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Dutch navigator Abel Janszoon Tasman, who sailed from Batavia (Jakarta) to investigate the practicality of a sea passage eastward to Chile and to explore New Guinea, skirted the southern shores of Tasmania this day in 1642.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1970</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>25</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1970, Japanese novelist Mishima Yukio and four members of his Shield Society, a private army formed to preserve Japan's martial spirit, seized a military headquarters in Tokyo, and he later committed seppuku.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1942</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>26</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Set in occupied Morocco during World War II, directed by Michael Curtiz, and starring Humphrey Bogart, Ingrid Bergman, and Paul Henreid, Casablanca premiered this day in 1942 and became one of Hollywood's most-revered films.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1895</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>27</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Through the will drawn up by Alfred Bernhard Nobel-the Swedish chemist, engineer, and industrialist who invented dynamite and other, more powerful explosives-the Nobel Prizes were established on this day in 1895.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1943</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>28</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Tehran Conference, attended by U.S. President Franklin D. Roosevelt, British Prime Minister Winston Churchill, and Soviet Premier Joseph Stalin, at which Stalin pressed for an invasion of France, opened this day in 1943.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1947</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>29</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1947, the United Nations General Assembly adopted a resolution (not implemented) calling for the partition of Palestine into two separate states-an Arab and a Jewish one-that would retain an economic union.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1966</Year>
      <Month>11</Month>
      <Day>30</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Barbados, an island nation in the Caribbean situated about 100 miles (160 km) east of the Windward Islands, had gained internal self-rule in 1961 and achieved its full independence from Britain on this day in 1966.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1955</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>1</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>This day in 1955, in violation of segregation laws in Montgomery, Alabama, Rosa Parks refused to surrender her bus seat to a white passenger and was arrested, sparking a 381-day bus boycott led by Martin Luther King, Jr.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1823</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>2</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Monroe Doctrine, which declared that the U.S. would not interfere in European affairs but that its sphere of interest included the entire Western Hemisphere, was enunciated by President James Monroe this day in 1823.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1984</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>3</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1984, a gas leak from a Union Carbide plant in Bhopal, India, spread over a populated area, resulting ultimately in 15,000 to 20,000 deaths and leaving some half million survivors with chronic medical ailments.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1533</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>4</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1533, the three-year-old who became Ivan the Terrible was proclaimed grand prince of Moscow upon the death of his father, Grand Prince Vasily III, with his mother ruling in Ivan's name until her death in 1538.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1484</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>5</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Innocent VIII condemned witchcraft this day in 1484 via papal bull, and subsequently he dispatched inquisitors to Germany to try witches and persecuted a chief exponent of Renaissance Platonism, Giovanni Pico della Mirandola.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1921</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>6</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The British government and Irish leaders Arthur Griffith, Michael Collins, and others signed the Anglo-Irish Treaty, establishing the Irish Free State as an independent member of the British Commonwealth this day in 1921.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1941</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>7</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1941, Japanese bombers launched a surprise aerial attack on the U.S. naval base at Pearl Harbor on the island of Oahu, Hawaii, precipitating the entry of the United States into World War II.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1980</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>8</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1980, British musician John Lennon-who rose to fame with the Beatles and had a successful solo career-was fatally shot by Mark David Chapman in New York City, causing a global outpouring of grief.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1990</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>9</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1990, Lech Walesa-who had led Solidarity, Poland's first independent trade union, and had received the Nobel Prize for Peace in 1983-won Poland's first direct presidential election by a landslide.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1768</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>10</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The first part of the first edition of the Encyclop?dia Britannica, the oldest continuously published and revised work in the English language, was published and advertised for sale in Edinburgh on this day in 1768.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1936</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>11</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Edward VIII, failing to win acceptance for his desire to marry American divorc?e Wallis Warfield Simpson, became the only British sovereign to voluntarily resign the crown, his abdication formally approved this day in 1936.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2000</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>12</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2000, the U.S. Supreme Court effectively awarded the presidency to George W. Bush, ruling that a fair recount of ballots in Florida could not be performed by the deadline for certifying the state's electors.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1642</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>13</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1642, Dutch navigator Abel Tasman sighted South Island, New Zealand, and later, mistaking the strait north of the island for a bay, believed he had found the west coast of a hypothetical southern continent.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1911</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>14</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>One of the greatest figures in the history of polar exploration was Norwegian explorer Roald Amundsen, who left Norway for Antarctica in June 1910 and on this day in 1911 became the first person to reach the South Pole.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1939</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>15</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Starring Vivien Leigh and Clark Gable, the film Gone with the Wind-a romantic tale of the American South during the Civil War adapted from the 1936 novel by Margaret Mitchell-premiered this day in Atlanta, Georgia, in 1939.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1773</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>16</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1773, in what is known as the Boston Tea Party, American colonists disguised as Mohawk Indians threw 342 chests of tea belonging to the British East India Company into Boston Harbor to protest a tax on tea.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1903</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>17</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1903 near Kitty Hawk, North Carolina, brothers Orville and Wilbur Wright made the first successful sustained flights in an airplane-Orville first, gliding 120 feet (36.6 metres) through the air in 12 seconds.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1865</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>18</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1865, by proclamation of the U.S. secretary of state, the Thirteenth Amendment to the Constitution, outlawing slavery, officially entered into force, having been ratified by the requisite states on December 6.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1998</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>19</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1998, the U.S. House of Representatives impeached President Bill Clinton, charging him with perjury and obstruction of justice, though Clinton was acquitted by the Senate the following month.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1999</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>20</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1999, 12 years after an agreement was reached between China and Portugal, several centuries of Portuguese rule ended in Macau when it became a special administrative region under Chinese sovereignty.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1898</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>21</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1898, having recently discovered polonium, future Nobel Prize winners Marie and Pierre Curie discovered the radioactive chemical element radium, a silvery white metal that would be used to treat cancer.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1894</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>22</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1894, on the basis of specious evidence and anti-Semitism, French army officer Alfred Dreyfus was sentenced to life in prison for treason, sparking a controversy that divided France for 12 years.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1995</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>23</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Aleksander Kwasniewski, formerly an apparatchik of Poland's ruling communist party, was sworn in as the country's president this day in 1995, having narrowly defeated Lech Walesa, Poland's first postcommunist president.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1814</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>24</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1814, the United States and Great Britain signed the Treaty of Ghent in Belgium, ending the War of 1812, marking a decline of American dependence on Europe, and stimulating a sense of U.S. nationalism.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1977</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>25</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info> Charlie Chaplin, the British comedic actor and director who is widely regarded as one of the most important figures in motion-picture history, died in Corsier-sur-Vevey, Switzerland.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>2004</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>26</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 2004, a large earthquake shook the Indian Ocean floor west of the island of Sumatra, triggering a devastating tsunami that swamped coastal areas from Thailand to Africa and killed more than 200,000 people.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1949</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>27</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>On this day in 1949, four years after nationalist revolutionary leader Sukarno had declared Indonesia's independence, formal sovereignty over the country was transferred from the Dutch to the United States of Indonesia.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1065</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>28</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The original Westminster Abbey, located in London, was consecrated and opened this day in 1065 by Edward the Confessor and became the site of coronations and other ceremonies of national significance in England.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1845</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>29</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The annexation of the Republic of Texas by the United States, approved by the U.S. Congress this day in 1845, sparked the Mexican War because land between the Rio Grande and the Nueces River was disputed territory.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1922</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>30</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>The Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, formed this day in 1922 with its capital in Moscow, eventually incorporated 15 republics and constituted (in area) the largest country in the world until its dissolution in 1991.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
  <OnThisDay>
    <Date>
      <Year>1857</Year>
      <Month>12</Month>
      <Day>31</Day>
    </Date>
    <Info>Ottawa, located in Ontario at the confluence of the Ottawa, Gatineau, and Rideau rivers and whose area was first described by Samuel de Champlain in 1613, was named the capital of Canada by Queen Victoria this day in 1857.</Info>
  </OnThisDay>
</ArrayOfOnThisDay>